Stein, Emanuel Papers 5888
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Emanuel Stein Papers
1976-1983
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Stein, Emanuel
5888
4 cubic feet
4 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
5725208
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 16, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 17, 2019
Biographical / Historical
1918 Born In St. Louis, Missouri
1928 New York University, B.S.
1930 New York University, A.M.
1933 New York University, Ph.D.
1930-31 N.Y.U., Teaching Fellow Economics
1931-38 N.Y.U., Instructor
1938-43 N.Y.U., Assistant Professor
1941 Editor of Labor Cases and Materials (with Carl Raushenbush)
1942-45 Regional War Regional Board 11 Pub. Member
1943-46 N.Y.U., Associate Professor
1946- N.Y.U., Professor
1946-51 Washington Square College, Acting Chairman Department of Economics
Chairman Social Science Group Graduate School of Arts and Science
1948-62 Executive Director, N.Y.U. Institute of Labor and Social Security
1948-62 Editor of Proceedings of N.Y.U. Annual Conference on Labor
1951-52 New York Regional W.S.B.
1955-67 N.Y.U., Head of Economics Department
1967-74 Professor of Humanities and Social Sciences
1974- Emeritus Professor
1974- Lecturer in Public and Business Administration
Member:
Panel Public Relations Employment Board
New York State, Office of Collective Bargaining
N.Y.C. Board overseers Jewish Theological Sem. Am.
New York State Board of Mediation
New Jersey Board of Mediation
National Academy Arbitrators
Mediation and Conciliation Service
Industrial Relation Research Association
Met. Economics Association (president 1960-61)
Phi Beta Kappa
Author of books in field
Editor: Board Editors Labor History
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5001 mf: American Association for Labor Legislation Records on Microfilm 5206-S: Local 1199 Executive Secretary Moe Foner Records 5293: New York State Teachers Association Records 5441: Eveline M. Burns Collection of Publications 5541: Philip Taft Papers 5619: ACWA Records 5680 OH: Local 1199 Oral History Project 5780/006: ILGWU Morris Sigman Correspondence 5780/102 P: ILGWU Justice Photographs 5780/178: ILGWU Charles Zimmerman Collection of Radical Pamphlets 6021/008: Theodore W. Kheel Books and Articles 6034: Rare Pamphlet Collection 6036/076 OH: Daniel Soyer ILGWU Heritage Project 6063: Emanuel Stein Additional Arbitration Files: Board of Education Hicksville Public Schools and Hicksville Congress of Teachers
Transport workers -- Labor unions.; Communication and traffic; Electricians; Absenteeism (Labor); Contracting out.; Insubordination.; Stein, Emanuel, 1908-1985; Bituminous Coal Operators Association; World Telegram; American Airlines.; Transport Workers Union of America.; General Electric Company.; World Telegram
5725208
- American Airlines Inc., 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- American Airlines Inc. New York, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- American Airlines, Inc., 1967-1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- American Airlines, Inc., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Scope and Contents
  April 8 1975
- American Airlines, Inc. NY Area Board of Adjustment, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Stenographic Record
- American Airlines, Inc. NY Area Board of Adjustment, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Contains 17 photographs
- American Airlines Inc. NY Area Board of Adjustment, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- American Airlines, Inc., 1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Courtroom transcript
- American Airlines, Inc., 1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- American Airlines Board of Adjustment, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- American Airlines Board of Adjustment, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  April 11 1980
- American Airlines, Inc., 1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  New York Area Board of Adjustment; June 23 1980
- American Airlines, Inc., 1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  June 23 1980
- American Airlines, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  December 16 1980
- American Airlines, Inc., 1980 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  May 15 1980; Infraction report
- American Airlines, Inc., 1981 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  March 3 1981
- Grievance Hearing American Airlines, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  March 19 1981
- American Airlines Board of Adjustment NY Area, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  June 3 1981
- American Airlines, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- American Airlines Board of Adjustment NY Area, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  June 29 1981
- American Airlines "Post-Hearing Brief of the Union", 1981 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  3/5/1981
- American Airlines, Inc., 1981 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  January 13 1981
- American Airlines, Inc., 1982 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  January 13 1982
- American Airlines Absenteeism Releases, 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- American Arbitration Association, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  September 23 1980
- American Arbitration Association, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Board of Higher Education of the City of New York; October 21 1980
- Affirmation of Michael D. Solomon, Esq., for Respondents, in Support of Motion to Dismiss, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- New York Supreme Court Appellate Division First Department, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- American Arbitration Association Voluntary Labor Arbitration Tribunal, 1971-1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  The City University of New York
- American Arbitration Association Voluntary Labor Arbitration Tribunal, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- American Arbitration Association, Administrator, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  April 21 1982
- American Arbitration Association, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  E.I. DuPont DeNemours; November 19 1981
- Arbitration between Chemical Workers Association and E.I. DuPont deNemours, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  November 19 1981
- Arbitration between Exxon Research and Engineering Company and Independent Laboratory Employees Union, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Exxon Research and Engineering Company and Independent Laboratory Employees Union, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  April 1 1981
- Exxon Research and Engineering Company and Independent Laboratory Employees Union, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- General Electric Company and IUE Radio and Machine Workers Local 492, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  September 16 1980
- The Arbitration Between IUE Radio and Machine Workers Local 492 and General Electric Company, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  June 3 1980
- International Union of Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers Local 492 and General Electric Co., 1980 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  7/25/1980
- International union of Electrical Radio and Machine Workers Local 761 and General Electric Company, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  July 29 1980
- General Electric Company and International Union of Electrical Radio and Machine Workers Local 761, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  September 22 1980
- International Union of Electrical Radio and Machine Workers Local 761 and General Electric Company, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  September 17 1981
- New England Telephone Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  September 16 1977
- New England Telephone Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  December 6 1977
- New England Telephone and Telegraph Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  November 28 1978
- New England Telephone and Telegraph Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  November 29 1978
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers and New England Telephone and Telegraph Company, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Received November 16 1979
- New England Telephone and Telegraph Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  June 20 1979
- New England Telephone and Telegraph Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  November 13 1979
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers and New England Telephone and Telegraph Company, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  Received February 11 1980
- Agreement between New England Telephone and Telegraph Company and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  September 26 1971
- Communications Workers of America, Local 1106 and New York Telephone Company (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Communications Workers of America, Local 1106 and New York Telephone, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  April 23 1980
- Communications Workers of America, Local 1106 and New York Telephone, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  April 24 1980
- Communications Workers of America, Local 1101 and New York Telephone, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  April 25 1980
- Communications Workers of America Local 1101 and New York Telephone, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  October 29 1980
- Communications Workers of America Local 1101 and New York Telephone, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  October 30 1980
- Communications Workers of America and New York Telephone, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  December 10 1980
- New York Telephone Company and Communications Workers of America, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  July 15 1981
- Communications Workers of America and New York Telephone Company, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  July 28 1983
- American Telephone and Telegraph Company, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Offer of Facilities for Use by other Common Carriers
- Professional Staff Congress/CUNY and Board of Trustees of the City University of New York, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  July 21 1981
- Notes on CWA Case (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Communications Workers of America Local 1106 Notes (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Agreement Between New York Telephone Company and Empire City Subway Company and Communications Workers of America, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  August 10 1980
- OPEIU Local 153 and Public Service Electric and Gas Co., 1979 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  June 26 1979
- OPEIU Local 153 and Public Service Electric and Gas Company, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  January 11 1980
- Public Service Electric and Gas Company and Public Utility Construction and Gas Appliance Workers, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  July 30 1981
- Local 804, IBT and United Parcel Service, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  June 18 1980
- Local 804, IBT and United Parcel Service, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  June 19 1980
- Brief on Behalf of the United Parcel Service, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  The Arbitration Between the Local 804, IBT and the United Parcel Service
- Local 804 Delivery and Warehouse Employees International Brotherhood of Teamsters, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  And the United Parcel Service
- Notes on the United Parcel Service Local 804 IBT Arbitration (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Supplemental Appendix, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  United Parcel Service and General Teamsters Local 174; June 8 1979
- Appendix (Box 3, Folder 17)
  United Parcel Service v. International Brotherhood of Teamsters
- Local 804 IBT and United Parcel Service, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  January 28 1981
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters and United Parcel Service, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  June 7 1982
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters and United Parcel Service, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  November 26 1981
- Arbitration between United Parcel Service and Local 804 International Brotherhood of Teamsters, 1974-1983 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- The Jewish Hospital and Medical Center of Brooklyn, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  December 31 1973,1974
- New York University Retired Faculty and Staff, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- American Airlines, Inc. and Transport Workers Union, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  July 1 1976
- American Airlines, Inc. and Transport Workers Union, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  July 19 1976
- American Airlines, Inc. and Transport Workers Union, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  July 29 1976
- American Airlines, Inc. and Transport Workers Union of America, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  March 6 1981
- Attendance Control Guidelines and the Sick Leave Benefit, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  American Airlines, Inc. August 1969
- Deirdre L Bergson and City University of New York, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- The Board of Higher Education of the City of new York (Queens College) and Deirdre L Bergson, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Local 203 International Union of Electrical Radio and Machine Workers of America and General Electric Company, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  September 10 1976
- International Union of Electrical Radio and Machine Workers and General Electric, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Deirdre L Bergson and Board of Higher Education and Professional Staff Congress/CUNY, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Litman, Friedman Kaufman and Asche
- Notes on the Matter of Arbitration between General Electric and IUE Radio and Machine Workers, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Employee Representative Meeting Slips, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- IUE Radio and Machine Workers and General Electric Company, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  July 9 1981
- International Union of Electrical Radio and Machine Workers and General Electric Company, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  June 12 1981
- IUE Radio and Machine Workers and General Electric Company, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  Assorted papers
- Transcript of Proceedings before Presidential Emergency Board No. 182, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  Involving a dispute between The Long Island Railroad Company and certain employees; February 1 1973
- Transcript No. 2 of Long Island Railroad Meeting (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Transcript of Proceeding of the National Mediation Board, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  Emergency Board No. 182; September 28 1972; Long Island Railroad Employee Dispute
- Transcript No. 4 LIRR Meetings (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Union's Rebuttal of Emergency Board No. 182 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  Union Brief, Edward G. Dougherty
- Mikropul and Local 418 International Brotherhood of Teamsters, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  February 24 1976
- Mikropul and Local 418, International Brotherhood of Teamsters, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  April 30 1976
- Mikropul and Local 418 International Brotherhood of Teamsters, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  April 12, 1976